it's no secret that a weight bench is a
vital piece of equipment for your home
gym and the rep fitness ab5000 may be
the best option available on the market
thanks to its unique adjustment
mechanism allowing the seat to slide
creating zero gap between the pads plus
it's able to withstand up to a thousand
pounds
and
it's comfortable
[Music]
what's up everybody it's jake back in
the barbie garage gym and in for review
today
i've got the rep fitness
ab5000 in this video i'm gonna walk you
through all the details of this weight
bench the features the price some pros
and cons and of course who should who
should not buy this weight bench before
we get started today i got to let you
know we have reviewed a lot of weight
benches on barbin.com and to find out
more just google barbin best weight
benches find out for yourself which one
we like best
all right so there's a lot to like about
this weight bench the ab5000 has a zero
gap mechanism meaning there's literally
zero gap between both the pads the seat
pad has five adjustments to go along
with the seven back pad adjustments plus
you can add a leg roller attachment to
turn this bench into an fid bench
meaning flat incline and decline
plus it's rated at a thousand pounds and
built with 11 gauge steel meaning
this thing's in it for the long haul and
it's strong enough even for the heaviest
of lifters now with all of that being
said there are a few potential cons that
you might run into with the ab5000
listed at 600 on the rep fitness website
this is a pretty expensive weight bench
and if you wanted the leg roller
attachment that's an extra 100 dollars
putting this over 700 purchase and while
the quality might make it worth it there
are options out there for a fraction of
the price if you're looking for a
strictly flat bench you may not be
interested in the available adjustments
here with the ab5000 and while it may be
portable thanks to the wheels this
thing's
pounds and trust me you're gonna feel
that weight which might make it
difficult to move around
let's dig into some money now there are
two pricing options available for you on
the rep fitness website the colored
options like this black one here are
gonna cost you about 600 bucks while the
clear coat that's gonna be around 680
and while i did mention the leg roller
attachment that's an extra hundred
dollars and they also feature a wider
back pad that's going to be a shade
under 90.
potentially making this weight bench
900. and i know that's expensive i know
that's an investment but thanks to the
high quality 11 gauge steel this weight
bench could last you 20 years
potentially even a lifetime
[Music]
all right so let's dig into the build
now of the ab5000 weighing in at a hefty
125 pounds this is a very sturdy weight
bench thanks to the addition of the
front foot it sticks out giving it that
extra stability it is made with the 11
gauge steel which is professional
quality that you'll most often find at a
mainstream gym the padding is firm but
at the same time it's pretty comfortable
and it's made with a non-slip vinyl
which will kind of give you some extra
traction when you get sweaty you're
laying on it working out on it and it
has a footprint of around eight square
feet so let's dig into the features now
of the ab5000 if you were to add on that
leg roller attachment it's going to
transform this bench into a full fid
bench meaning flat incline and decline
allowing you to focus on all three
portions of your chest as well as
unlocking the ability to work your core
and because of the laser cut markings
you'll find that you have no problem
finding that sweet spot adjusting for
each individual exercise and thanks to
the zero gap mechanism here you have
zero gap at all no matter where this
thing is positioned you will not have to
deal with that awkward gap on your lower
back and because of the wheels and the
handle you can move this bench around
your weight room at ease so i'm going to
walk you through everything that this
ab5000 has to offer as i mentioned this
does have a firm padding but at the same
time it's pretty comfortable and it's
made with that non-slip vinyl which may
give you some extra traction while
you're working out and as you can see
there is no gap here well that's every
single adjustment that you can think of
and this is made possible due to the
seat being able to slide back and forth
and to do that all you have to do is
pull down on this knob right here you
can look you can do it with one hand no
problem once you find where you want it
it locks in place and it's not going
anywhere as i mentioned also this does
have a handle on it but i found that
this is a little bit of an awkward angle
there are some other benches out there
that have a more i guess grip friendly
angle when you're looking to grab it
this is built with 11 gauge steel though
which is pretty much the best quality
you could ask for
so when it comes to adjusting your seat
pad you do have five different
adjustments available to you to do that
all you have to do is pull out on this
knob and you can make it go down you can
make it go up really whatever you want
and you can always find that right angle
thanks to the laser cut degree markings
for the seat pad and the back pad
same exact scenario when it comes to
adjusting your back pad but if you come
around here now i'm going to raise this
up
and we're going to check out if you were
to add on that leg roller attachment all
you got to do
pop this cap out
and you can easily slide it in here and
you as you see
you have two different knobs right here
unscrew them and once it's in there just
tighten them in it'll secure that into
place
and last but not least you do have
wheels on this bench making it portable
so you can move it around your home gym
so who should buy the ab5000 well if
you're somebody like myself who can't
stand that gap that adjustable weight
benches often bring you you'll love that
this one does not have that whatsoever
and since it's built with 11 gauge steel
and rated at a thousand pounds this
could last you potentially a lifetime
and if you want to incorporate both
incline and decline bench press you can
easily do so if you choose to add on
that extra leg roller attachment so what
about the people who should avoid the
ab5000 well price is always a factor
this is listed at 600
but if you were to add on all the extra
attachments it's going up to 900 it's a
very expensive weight bench rep fitness
does offer one for about 300
but the high quality and the versatility
of this bench may make it worth that
price tag
and like i said it's 125 pounds that's
pretty heavy you could always find a
weight bench that's lighter out there
and third while space may not be
something you think about when you're
purchasing a weight bench make sure you
have enough because this weight bench
does require around eight square feet of
space so make sure you have that before
making it your newest addition
that's about all i have for you guys
today on the ab5000 i personally think
this is one of the best weight benches
on the market thanks to its versatility
and the features the adjustment
mechanism leaves zero gap whatsoever
while you're using it and plus it's
built with 11 gauge steel making it as
sturdy as they come thanks for watching
i hope this video was helpful and gave
you some insight on what this weight
bench has to offer stay on the lookout
for my next video and in the meantime
head over to barbin.com and you can read
up more about this bench just google
barbin rep fitness ab5000 review and you
can read about everything we discussed
here today see y'all next time
[Music]
you